Guide to the Paul Langland Papers, 1926-2018 MSS.253
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Video recordings, 1977-2004, undated; 203302
  - Subseries A: Video Elements, 1977-2004, undated; 203304
    - Tape 7, CSK Duets and Solos, November 30, 1998; ID: 253.0224; 205291 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0224, Case 253.0224)
      Duration: 1 hour 51 minutes
    - Tape 8, CSK AW including Scalpel, December 3, 1998; ID: 253.0225; 205292 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0225, Case 253.0225)
    - Tape 9, Venus Group Improv., December 2, 1998; ID: 253.0226; 205293 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0226, Case 253.0226)
      Duration: 1 hour 47 minutes
    - Tape 10, Synovial, Venus Duet Phrases, December 4, 1998; ID: 253.0227; 205294 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0227, Case 253.0227)
    - Tape 11, Alex on Floor, AW Standing Barr, Arterial, December 7, 1998; ID: 253.0228; 205295 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0228, Case 253.0228)
      Duration: 1 hour 37 minutes
    - Tape 12, Fluids Projects, Self Directed (Warm Up), December 9, 1998; ID: 253.0229; 205296 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0229, Case 253.0229)
      Duration: 1 hour 15 minutes
    - 25th Anniversary Danspace Project Silver Series: Volume Two, Part 1, Channel Z, March 28, 1999; ID: 253.0232; 205299 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0232, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0232)
      Duration: 55 minutes
    - Spontaneous Combustion Cabaret, Northampton, Massachusetts, Various Acts Ending with Outtahand, 1999; ID: 253.0087; 203393 (Box 35, Case 253.0087)
      Duration: 1 hour 16 minutes
    - 1. Heat, Judson Church, New York 2. Honor, Tisch School of Art, New York, 1. April 24, 2000/ 2. May 17, 1998; ID: 253.0090; 203396 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0090)
    - Jungle Breath at Dixon Place, May 30, 2000; ID: 253.0091; 203397 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0091)
    - 7th World (Really the 6th) Danspace Project (Master), December 1, 2000; ID: 253.0092; 205302 (Box 36, Case 253.0092)
      Wendell Beavers, Paul Langland, Mary Overlie
    - Heat at University of California, Davis, April 10, 2001; ID: 253.0236; 205303 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0236)
    - 1. Animas 2. Heat, University of California, Davis, April 14, 2001; ID: 253.0095; 203401 (Box 36, Case 253.0095)
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave - Amherst College, June 16, 2001; ID: 253.0096; 205301 (Box 36, Case 253.0096)
      Duration: 15 minutes
    - Rooms and Buildings, October 2001; ID: 253.0098; 203404 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0098, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0098)
      Duration: 1 hour 21 minutes
    - Getting Ready to Really Leave, Movement Research at Judson Church, March 18, 2002; ID: 253.0104; 203410 (Box 36, Case 253.0104)
      Duration: 17 minutes
    - Scratch, (Improv Festival 10), Danspace Project, November 29, 2001; ID: 253.0099; 203405 (Box 36, Case 253.0099)
      Duration: 23 minutes
    - Rooms and Buildings, Barnard, April 5, 2002; ID: 253.0008; 203313 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0008)
    - Du[c] Master for 4 Solos Excerpts, October 2003; ID: 253.0097; 203403 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0097)
      Original format: DV mini
    - Scratch - My Improv Festival, December 2001; ID: 253.0100; 203406 (Box 36, Case 253.0100)
    - Whoopee in the Dark, University Settlement, New York, October 3, 2002; ID: 253.0004; 205304 (Box 34, Case 253.0004)
      Duration: 1 hour 7 minutes
    - Four Solos, Jewel Theatre, Luther College, January 9, 2004; ID: 253.0109; 203415 (Box 36, Case 253.0109)
    - Self Erasure Pieces (In Progress) Rehearsal Tape, 2002; ID: 253.0238; 205305 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0238, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0238)
    - Storyteller, excerpt from Whoopee in the Dark, Movement Research at Judson, March 3, 2003; ID: 253.0239; 205306 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0239, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0239)
    - TSL, Four Solos (Master), July 10, 2004; ID: 253.0240; 205307 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0240, Case 253.0240)
      Duration: 50 minutes
    - Z Boys, October 1984, 2004; ID: 253.0003; 203308 (Box 34, Case 253.0003)
    - Alabama, undated; ID: 253.0114; 203420 (Box 36, Case 253.0114)
    - Allan Wayne Tape, undated; ID: 253.0115; 203421 (Box 36, Case 253.0115)
      Duration: 1 hour 11 minutes
    - 1. Coffee 2. Trio: Angels and Apes 3. Trio: St Mark's Church, 1993; ID: 253.0006; 203311 (Box 34, Case 253.0006)
    - Boomerang, undated; ID: 253.0121; 203514 (Box 36, Case 253.0121)
    - Brendan and Paul Fuck Around, undated; ID: 253.0116; 203509 (Box 36, Case 253.0116)
    - Boomerang, Edited, undated; ID: 253.0122; 203515 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0122)
    - 20 Minute Black, Class Acts Title, undated; ID: 253.0123; 203516 (Box 36, Case 253.0123)
    - Channel Z at Pepsico, Preliminary Edit, undated; ID: 253.0243; 205310 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0243)
    - Channel Z -Advertisement, undated; ID: 253.0244; 205311 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0244, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0244)
      Duration: 2 minutes
    - Channel Z Studio Live- 1. Ensemble 2. Singing, etc. 3. Randy (another time), undated; ID: 253.0246; 205313 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0246)
    - Section 6, 2 Eyes video, April 22, undated; ID: 253.0113; 203419 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0113, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0113)
    - Domestic Virtue, Perf., undated; ID: 253.0125; 203518 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0125, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0125)
      Duration: 1 hour 52 minutes
      Camera: Moises Kaufman
    - Domestic Virtue, undated; ID: 253.0126; 203519 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0126, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0126)
      Duration: 56 minutes
    - Domestic Virtue (Master), undated; ID: 253.0127; 203520 (Box 39, Case 253.0127)
    - Ellis Island, undated; ID: 253.0128; 203521 (Box 36, Case 253.0128)
    - E.T.W Festival Day, undated; ID: 253.0129; 203522 (Box 36, Case 253.0129)
      Duration: 1 hour 57 minutes
    - Four Pieces- 1. Boomerang 2. Jungle Breath 3. Domestic Virtue 4. Rapture, undated; ID: 253.0130; 203523 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0130)
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff, Domestic Virtue - Barbara Hofrenning
    - Domestic Virtue (Master), undated; ID: 253.0150; 203543 (Box 39, Case 253.0150)
      Duration: 1 hour 48 minutes
    - Dolmen Music/Meredith Monk; Gala Concert for The Kitchen, April 27, 2004; ID: 253.0005; 203310 (Box 34, Case 253.0005)
    - The Ghost of a Flea at PS 122, Tight Angle, undated; ID: 253.0131; 203524 (Box 36, Case 253.0131)
    - The Ghost of a Flea at PS 122, Wide Angle, undated; ID: 253.0132; 203525 (Box 36, Case 253.0132)
    - Helena Kolda, 11 Shorts, undated; ID: 253.0133; 203526 (Box 36, Case 253.0133)
      Content: [1] -- Mingus [2] -- The Last Days of Marienbad [3] -- Focusing [4] -- Precarious Positions [5] -- 3 Poems by Honor Moore [6] -- Bachanalia [7] -- Fire and Water [8] -- All of Me [9] -- Ode to Manhattan Yellow Pages [10] -- Noon Song [11] -- The Saints
    - Honda Commercial Auditions, undated; ID: 253.0134; 203527 (Box 36, Case 253.0134)
    - 1. Jonah 2. Spectra, Brain Flow, undated; ID: 253.0135; 203528 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0135)
      - Excerpts, Master, 1984; 1987; ID: 253.0166; 203559 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0166)
        Orignal format: VHS
    - 1. Combing the Will 2. Jungle Breath, undated; ID: 253.0136; 203529 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0136)
      Participants: Barbara Hofrenning - Combing the Will, Daniel Lepkoft - Jungle Breath
    - Kinetic Fairy Tale (Master), undated; ID: 253.0138; 203531 (Box 36, Case 253.0138)
    - I Will Not Be Sad In This World, undated; ID: 253.0248; 205315 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0248, Case 253.0248)
      Written and Directed by Ping Chong
    - 1. Lumberjack Jig 2. Raw Footage, undated; ID: 253.0140; 203533 (Box 36, Case 253.0140)
      Duration: 30 minutes
    - Lory's Shots - Ferreri and Chinatown, undated; ID: 253.0141; 203534 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0141)
      Original format: Hi 8mm
    - 1. Man and Machine 2. Waterfall 3. Jonah, undated; ID: 253.0002; 203307 (Box 34, Case 253.0002)
      Duration: 21 minutes
    - 1. Man and Machine 2. Waterfall (Master edit), undated; ID: 253.0142; 203535 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0142)
    - Master Excerpts- 1. Blue Sail Fish 2. Filibuster II 3. Current Stream, undated; ID: 253.0241; 205308 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0241)
      Original format: 3/4 in Umatic
    - Master Excerpts, Channel Z- 1. Blue Sail Fish 2. Filibuster II 3. Current Stream, undated; ID: 253.0242; 205309 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0242)
    - Miguel Azcue Resume Tape, undated; ID: 253.0144; 203537 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0144)
    - Turtle Dreams - Monk and Greenaway (PBS Version), undated; ID: 253.0145; 203538 (Box 36, Case 253.0145)
    - Meredith Monk, undated; ID: 253.0055; 203360 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0055)
      Credit: Peter Greenway
    - Moses [Pendleton], undated; ID: 253.0151; 203544 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0151)
    - Movement Track, Third Night, undated; ID: 253.0038; 203343 (Box 34, Case 253.0038)
    - Naked Nude, Channel Z, undated; ID: 253.0245; 205312 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0245, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0245)
      Duration: 41 minutes
      Featuring Paul Langland, Dianne Madden, and Nina Martin. Camera: Randy Warshaw.
    - Normal Kansas, Act 1, undated; ID: 253.0146; 203539 (Box 36, Case 253.0146)
    - Normal Kansas, Act 2, undated; ID: 253.0147; 203540 (Box 36, Case 253.0147)
    - Normal Kansas, Act 3, undated; ID: 253.0148; 203541 (Box 36, Case 253.0148)
    - Paul Langland and Barbara Hofrenning Sampler, undated; ID: 253.0149; 203542 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0149)
    - N.Y Contact Group at Pratt - Tape 1, undated; ID: 253.0009; 203314 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0009)
      Original format: 1/2 inch open reel
    - N.Y. Contacters at Pratt - Tape 2, undated; ID: 253.0010; 203315 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0010)
    - Psychoballet, Cuba, undated; ID: 253.0152; 203545 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0152)
    - Rapture, undated; ID: 253.0153; 203546 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0153)
    - Retazos, Danza-Teatro, Cuba, undated; ID: 253.0155; 203548 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0155)
    - Section Five, Inwood Park, Peter and Lisa Pieces, undated; ID: 253.0156; 203549 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0156)
    - 1. Shnock by Paul Langland 2. Halfshell by Paul Langland, undated; ID: 253.0157; 203550 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0157, Box Digitized Access Files, File 253.0157)
    - Source Material Self Erasure, undated; ID: 253.0158; 203551 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0158)
    - Paul Langland Title Tape, undated; ID: 253.0159; 203552 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0159)
    - Transit Mass by NYU Experimental Theatre Wing, undated; ID: 253.0160; 203553 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0160)
    - The Travelogue Series, Number 2, Act III, Chacon, undated; ID: 253.0161; 203554 (Box 37, Case 253.0161)
      Credit: Meredith Monk and Ping Chong
    - The Travelogue Series, Number 4, Act II, Venice/Milan, undated; ID: 253.0162; 203555 (Box 37, Case 253.0162)
    - Turtle Dreams at Plexus -- Left Side (Unedited Footage), undated; ID: 253.0164; 263744 (Box 37, Case 253.0164)
      Duration: 1 hour 1 minute
    - A Woodcutters Dream, undated; ID: 253.0163; 203556 (Box 37, Case 253.0163)
    - TV, undated; ID: 253.0165; 203558 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0165)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0167; 203560 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0167)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0168; 203561 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0168)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0169; 203562 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0169)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0170; 203563 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0170)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0171; 203564 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0171)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0172; 203565 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0172)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0173; 203566 (Box 37, Media ID: 253.0173)
    - Print, undated; ID: 253.0174; 203567 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0174)
      Original format: Film reel
    - Emotional Corridors, undated; ID: 253.0175; 203568 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0175)
      Currently unavailable.
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0176; 203569 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0176)
    - Self Erasure Work Tape (Master), undated; ID: 253.0249; 205316 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0249)
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0251; 205318 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0251)
      Currently unavailable until duplications occur.
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 253.0250; 205317 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0250)
- Series VII: Sound recordings, 1977-1997, undated; 204551
  Series VII consists of audio recordings related to Paul Langland's performances, largely of his own choreography and from his time performing with Meredith Monk's company. Sound recordings are currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
  Series VII is arranged chronologically. Undated material is arranged alphabetically following the dated material.
  Audio materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Center, June 8, 1977; ID: 253.0252; 206938 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0252)
  - Mount Carmel Baptist Church Seniors Club, June 15, 1977; ID: 253.0253; 206939 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0253)
    Original format: Audiocassette
  - Side A: C. Pandal Workshop Side B: Candle Dance, November 8, 1983; ID: 253.0254; 206940 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0254)
  - Dance Class, 108 Wooster, December 18, 1984; ID: 253.0255; 207237 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0255)
  - J. Swaggart, Drugs, Gays, Rapture, Ultimatum, December 5, 1985; ID: 253.0256; 207238 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0256)
  - Improvising with David Darline, I: Melodic Improvisation and Rhythmic Improvisation, 1987; ID: 253.0257; 207239 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0257)
  - Sade A: Bix Bidebeck Side B: Danny and Paul, March 9, 1988; ID: 253.0258; 207240 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0258)
  - Danny and Paul, January 1990; ID: 253.0259; 207241 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0259)
  - Danny and Paul Rehersals, April 1990; ID: 253.0260; 207242 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0260)
  - Side A: Danny and Paul; Side B: Danny and Paul, February 10, 1990; March 6, 1990; ID: 253.0261; 207243 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0261)
  - Danny and Paul, Jonah Duet, July 1990; ID: 253.0262; 207244 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0262)
  - Interview with Paul Langland on Allan Wayne, August 25, 1996; ID: 253.0263; 207245 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0263)
  - Interview with Paul Langland on Allan Wayne - Part Two, August 25, 1996; ID: 253.0264; 207246 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0264)
  - Tape for Paul langland by DJ Ganesha Del Mar, January 31, 1997; ID: 253.0265; 207247 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0265)
  - AAt Talks on Theater School and Scottish Bagpipes, Undated; ID: 253.0266; 207248 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0266)
  - Bo's Entrance, Undated; ID: 253.0267; 207249 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0267)
  - Boneyard, Undated; ID: 253.0268; 207250 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0268)
  - Breathing Clicks, Undated; ID: 253.0269; 207251 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0269)
  - Cherry or Cherries, Chery's in Back, Undated; ID: 253.0270; 207252 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0270)
  - Dolmen Music Solos, Undated; ID: 253.0271; 207253 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0271)
  - Side A: Dolmen Music and Monk Piano Side B: Turtle Dreams, Undated; ID: 253.0272; 207254 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0272)
  - Drums Effect, Undated; ID: 253.0273; 207255 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0273)
  - Side A: Emotional Corridors, Beethoven Side B: Vachtumschlä, Undated; ID: 253.0274; 207256 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0274)
  - Fame and Money, Success, Undated; ID: 253.0275; 207257 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0275)
  - Fight Dance, Undated; ID: 253.0276; 207258 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0276)
  - Side A: Ghost of a Flea and Jungle Breath Side B: Jazz, Undated; ID: 253.0277; 207259 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0277)
  - Glenn and Nate, Tape 1, Undated; ID: 253.0278; 207260 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0278)
  - Heart Beat, Undated; ID: 253.0279; 207261 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0279)
  - Jerry Goldman War Stories: IV, In Combat, Undated; ID: 253.0280; 207262 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0280)
  - Jonah, Part 1, Undated; ID: 253.0281; 207263 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0281)
  - Jonah, Drone, Undated; ID: 253.0282; 207264 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0282)
  - Jonah, Part 2, Undated; ID: 253.0283; 207265 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0283)
  - Jonah, Dub, Undated; ID: 253.0284; 207266 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0284)
  - Jungle Breath, Slow, Undated; ID: 253.0285; 207267 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0285)
  - La Vien Mix, Undated; ID: 253.0286; 207268 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0286)
  - Mr. Natural, Test Mix, Undated; ID: 253.0287; 207269 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0287)
  - Side A: Mr. Natural, Test Mix Side B: Channel Z Intro. Music - Aboriginal, Undated; ID: 253.0288; 207270 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0288)
  - Offeratory Song, End of Sermon, Undated; ID: 253.0289; 207271 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0289)
  - Side A: Paul's Story of Egypt Side B: Danny and Paul Voice, Undated; ID: 253.0290; 207272 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0290)
  - Phil Glass, Undated; ID: 253.0291; 207273 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0291)
  - Preset Music, Before and After Show, Section 6, Undated; ID: 253.0292; 207274 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0292)
  - Robert Ashley Side A: Private Parts Side B: Automatic Writing, Undated; ID: 253.0293; 207275 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0293)
  - Robert Burns, Undated; ID: 253.0294; 207276 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0294)
  - Rudie Berkhout, Spirit Songs, Undated; ID: 253.0295; 207277 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0295)
  - Smak Mix, Undated; ID: 253.0296; 207278 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0296)
  - Steps, Undated; ID: 253.0297; 207279 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0297)
  - Strings, Undated; ID: 253.0298; 207280 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0298)
  - Swaggart, Last Tape Rehersal Sketches, Undated; ID: 253.0299; 207281 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0299)
  - Turtle Dreams, Parts 1 and 2 - Mono, Undated; ID: 253.0300; 207282 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0300)
  - Turtle Dreams Cha Cha Rehersal, Undated; ID: 253.031; 207283 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.031)
  - Virgil Dance, Undated; ID: 253.0302; 207284 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0302)
  - Waterfall, Digridu, Undated; ID: 253.0303; 207285 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0303)
  - Western, #2, Undated; ID: 253.0304; 207286 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0304)
  - Untitled, Undated; ID: 253.0305; 207287 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0305)
  - Untitled, Undated; ID: 253.0306; 207288 (Box 33, Media ID: 253.0306)
- Series VIII: Vinyl Sound Recordings, 1973-1984; 223759
  Series VIII consists of four vinyl records, including Meredith Monk's "Dolman Music" on which Paul Langland provides vocals. Paul Langland
  Series VIII is arranged chronologically.
  Vinyl recordings have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Meredith Monk, Our Lady of Late; Minona Records, 1973; 225731 (Box 32)
  - Meredith Monk, Songs from the Hill/Tablet; Wergo, 1979; 225730 (Box 32)
  - Meredith Monk, Dolman Music; ECM, 1981; 225729 (Box 32)
  - Better an Old Demon than a New God; Giorno Poetry Records, 1984; 225728 (Box 32)
- Series IX: Data Storage, 1977-1985; undated; 223760
  Series IV consists of one data CD and 2 floppy disks. These disks include files and photographs.
  Series IV is arranged chronologically
  Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Meredith Monk Company Photographs - CD, 1977-1985; 223764 (Box 32)
  - Files Floppy Disk, 1984; 223765 (Box 32)
  - Almost Rapture floppy disk, undated; 223766 (Box 32)
- Series X: Objects, 2011, undated; 223761
  Series X consists of two costumes and a special edition Coke bottle.
  - Costume - Hat, undated; 223768 (Box 29)
  - Costume - Shirt, undated; 223769 (Box 30)
  - La Mama 50th Anniversary Coke Bottle, 2011; 223770 (Box 31)
- Series XI: 2015 Accretion, 2014-2015; 277300; .25 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box.
  This series consists of awards, event programs, performance notes, and articles featuring Paul Langland.
  - "Meredith Monk in Conversation with Paul Langland," Movement Research Performing Arts Journal, 2015; 277301 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - "Winter Dances" Preview, 2014-2015; 277302 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - "Marfa Motion" by Nancy Wozny, Texas Monthly, 2015 May; 277303 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - "Screening Room," Andrea Kleine; The Chocolate Factory, 2014 December; 277304 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Planet, 92nd Street Y, Simone Forti, Pooh Kaye, Langland, Sally Silvers, 2014 December; 277305 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Langland Programs, 2015; 277306 (Box 43, Folder 6)
- Series XII. 2016-2017 Accretions, 1986-2016; 1.50 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 oversize box.; 4 Gigabytes in 19 computer files
  This accretion to the Paul Langland Papers consists of paper and electronic files related to Langland's projects, performances, teaching, and professional involvement with modern dance techniques, including programs, printed email correspondence, and other ephemera.
  - NYU Improvisation Symposium and Ensemble Practicing Overtime Panel, 2015-2016 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1986-2016 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Andrea Kleine, 2014 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - The Total People -- 600 Highwaymen, 2016 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Fred Holland Memorial, 2016 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Langland Retrospective, 2016 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Standing in Space by Mary Overlie, 2016 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Posters, 1990s-2000s (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Angels of Swedenborg 2011 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_2)
  - Digital Duets Langland La MaMa, 2012 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_3)
  - Virtualab -- Langland at Culture Hub La MaMa, 2011 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_4)
  - Eterniday Talkback, 2013 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_5)
- Series XIII. 2018 Accretion, 2005-2018, undated; .25 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box.; 2 Gigabytes in 14 computer files
  - Printed Email Correspondence, 2018 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Screening Room, 2015-2017 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Sally Silvers -- Roulette, Tenderizer, 2017 (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
  - Meredith Monk, 2013-2017 (Box 48, Folder 5-6)
  - Diane Torr, 2017 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Programs, 2017-2018 (Box 48, Folder 8-9)
  - Meredith Monk Neue Töne aus der Neuen Welt, undated (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_6)
  - Cigarettes, Reading, Masturbation and Boys: A Film by Diane Torr, 2005 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_7)
  - Them: Cochrane, Cooper, Houston-Jones, undated (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_253_ER_8)
- OVERSIZE Series I: Files, 1973-2011, undated; 223131
  Oversize Series I is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Titles are orignial unless otherwise noted with square brackets.
  - ACDFA [American College Dance Festival Association, 1988; 223211 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Cliffs of Desperes, 1996; 223212 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Contact Improv, 1984, undated; 223213 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Domestic Virtue, 1988-1989; 223214 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Edinburgh Fringe, Ricky DeMarco Student Workshop, 1973; 223215 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Germany, 1986; 223216 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Letters- Paul Langland Responses, undated; 223217 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Movement Research Spring Gala, 2011; 223218 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - [Retazos/Danza Teatro], undated; 223219 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reviews- The Other Voice, 1981; 223220 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Visual Art/Film, 1987; 223221 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Notebooks and Planners, 1974-1976; 231743
  - Black Bound Sketchbook 1: "Anatomy for Dancers", 1974 - 1976; 231744 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Black Bound Sketchbook 2: "Contact Improvisation" and "Movement Arts Class at Senior Citizens Center", 1975 - 1976; 231745 (Box 42, Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Posters, Programs and Flyers, 1975-2000; 223132
  Series IV is arranged into two subseries, reflecting Paul Langland's original organization. Subseries A is arranged by artist and Subseries B is arranged by venue. Any additional material that was not assigned an original category has been arranged alphabetically by venue, and is listed at the end of the series.